She was a perfect doll. Now she's the real thing.
Life-Size is a family, comedy, fantasy film directed by Mark Rosman.
Sad and lonely after the death of her mother, Casey
would do anything to see her again.
But when a series of mystic mishaps mistakenly brings her fashion doll
“Eve” to life instead, it changes Casey’s world forever!
Casey Stuart, played by Lindsay Lohan.
Eve, played by Tyra Banks.
Ben Stuart, played by Jere Burns.
Drew McDonald, played by Anne Marie DeLuise.
Richie, played by Garwin Sanford.
Phil, played by Tom Butler.
Life-Size is a 2000 American fantasy comedy television film directed by
Mark Rosman and starring Lindsay Lohan and Tyra Banks.
It originally premiered on March 5, 2000, on ABC as part
of The Wonderful World of Disney block.
Lohan portrays a young girl who casts a magic spell to bring back her deceased mother and,
instead, accidentally brings to life her fashion doll, played by Banks.
The film then follows their relationship as the doll creates
havoc while trying to fit into the real world.
Life-Size was popular among its demographic, developing a cult following that frequently revisited and reexamined it
in the years following its release, and generated a sequel 18 years after the original broadcast.
It is considered a didactic children's film that set the tone for doll-inspired movies and is perceived by many fans as "the first
live-action Barbie movie" due to the similarities between the two dolls despite not having the rights to the official character.
The film made its streaming debut on Disney+ in November 2025, after
previously never having been available through digital platforms.
The sequel, titled Life-Size 2: A Christmas Eve, premiered on
December 2, 2018 on Freeform with Banks reprising her role.
In 2020, Banks announced another sequel was in the works.
The film explores themes of american football, sorcery,
single father, doll, death of mother.
The tone is lighthearted.